# **Chance York**

E-mail | LinkedIn | Bluesky | Google Scholar

#### **ABOUT**

**Hello!** I'm a quantitative user researcher with a Ph.D. in mass communication, which is the social scientific study of media selection and effects. In my spare time, I like to garden, hike, bike, read sci-fi, tinker in R, and build stuff with my hands. I live in Akron, Ohio. My work-related superpowers are deck design, storytelling complex data, and multivariate statistics.

#### TOOLS

**Programs:** R, Stata, SPSS, Excel, Miro, User Testing, Qualtrics, Alchemer, Figma, Slack, G Suite, BigQuery (novice) **Methods:** Surveys (gen pop, in product, log merged), A/B & factorial experiments, text analysis, in-depth interviews

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### STAFF QUANTITATIVE USER RESEARCHER

March 2023 - present

Mozilla Corporation - (remote) San Francisco, CA

- Research specializations: Revenue and monetization, product choice
- Lead end-to-end quantitative research: Scoping, planning, fielding, analyzing, and communicating the results of general population, in-product and log-merged surveys, as well as in-depth interviews as needed
  - o To date, delivered 6 high-visibility projects with actionable, strategic and business-focused insights
  - Projects have focused on market sizing, competitive analysis, benchmarking, trend analysis, and exploratory/generative research in emerging problem spaces
  - Methods used: Log-merged in-product surveys, gen pop surveys, in-depth interviews
- Develop standardized research materials like sampling guides, methods explainers, reusable question sets
- Serve as editorial board member of the Journal of User Experience Research (JUX)
- Share learnings externally at conferences like the 2024 Quant UX Con and in academic research journals

#### SENIOR QUANTITATIVE USER RESEARCHER

July 2021 - February 2023

Mozilla Corporation - (remote) San Francisco, CA

- Developed Firefox's first core longitudinal in-product survey and companion R analytics architecture
  - Maintained and promoted this (^) survey and its R architecture internally, delivering 8 talks on learnings from quantitative metrics and qualitative text analysis
  - Championed this program until its successful integration into 2 unique product OKRs
- Led 4 end-to-end quantitative survey projects on the attitudes and behaviors of internet users
  - One survey project on browser choice gained C-suite level visibility, changing internal mental models of user behavior surrounding our core product
  - o Deck designs partly inspired a research design hire to maintain excellence across the team
- Shared learnings externally at media and information science conferences and academic journals
- Note: This started as a contract position set to end December 2021, but converted to FTE November 2021

### **TENURED ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR**

August 2014 - June 2021

Kent State University - Kent, OH

- Published quantitative user research in internationally recognized journals and books (see my CV)
- Developed and taught courses in quantitative methods & statistics, including Ph.D. level courses
- Mentored Ph.D. and master's students on data-intensive dissertations, theses, and course projects

# **EDUCATION**

**Ph.D., MASS COMMUNICATION**Louisiana State University - Baton Rouge, LA (4.0 GPA) Focused on user choice in emerging media spaces, media effects on user behavior August 2010 - May 2014